Robert S. McNamara Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Part I: Organizations, 1968-2002 (Box I:38-77)
  - Council on Foreign Relations
    - Luncheon in honor of McNamara, 1986
    - Meetings, 1994
      - June 10, “Population and Our Global Future,” New York, N.Y.
      - Oct.. 7-10, National Committee on United States-China Relations, Pocantico Hills, N.Y.
  - David K. E. Bruce Endowment Committee, 1979-1988
  - Doctors Without Borders USA, 1991
  - Drug Strategies, 1997-1999
  - East African Development Bank, 1986-1996, (2 folders)
  - East-West Center, 1989-1993
  - East-West Development Corp. (Mogilev Region), 1988-1989 See also Container I:10, Lurvink, Frans
  - Economists Against the Arms Race, 1991
  - Economists Allied for Arms Reduction
    - General, 1992-1995
    - Symposium, Tokyo, Japan, 1998 (Box I:49)
  - Eisenhower Seminar, 1985-1991
  - Eminent Persons Group, meetings, 1992-1994, (2 folders)
  - Enterprise Foundation
    - Correspondence, 1983-1999, (2 folders)
    - Meetings
      - 1988, Jan. 5, Board of Directors, Washington, D.C., 1987-1988
      - 1998, Nov. 11-12, Board of Directors, Charlotte, N.C., 1995-1998
      - 1999, Aug. 16, Long-range Planning Committee, Charlotte, N.C., 1998-1999
    - Reports and printed matter, 1984-1990, 1999-2000, (3 folders) (Box I:50)
  - Environmental Development Consultants, 1993-1995
  - Euro-Arab Arbitration System, 1986-1988
  - European Bank for Reconstruction and Development
    - General
      - 1990-1991, (2 folders)
      - 1992-1993 (Box I:51)
    - Meeting, Business Advisory Council, Prague, Czech Republic (Sept. 1992), 1991-1992
  - European Center for International Security, 1988-1989
  - Foundation for Hellenic Culture, 1993-1994
  - Friends of Institute for a Democratic Alternative for South Africa, 1987-1992, (2 folders)
  - Fundación Arias para la Paz y el Progreso Humano, 1990-1991
  - Global Coalition for Africa
    - African Population Advisory Committee and AIDS prevention programs, 1992-1999
    - Agriculture
      - 1991-1992
      - 1993, 1999-2000 (Box I:52)
    - Conferences and meetings
      - 1991, Sept. 9-10, first Advisory Committee meeting, Paris, France
      - 1992, Oct. 27, cochairmens' meeting, Gaborone, Botswana
      - 1993
        - June 9-11, Advisory Committee, Cotonou, Benin
          - General, 1993, (2 folders)
          - Policy papers, 1993
        - Oct. 5-6, Tokyo International Conference on African Development, Tokyo, Japan (Box I:53)
          - Agenda and briefing book, 1993
          - General, 1993
      - 1994
        - Jan. 29-31, cochairmens' meeting, Gaborone, Botswana
        - June 2-3, Advisory Committee, Harare, Zimbabwe
          - Agenda and briefing book, 1994
          - Background material, 1993-1994
          - General, 1994
      - 1995
        - June 6-13, cochairmens' meeting, Accra, Ghana, 1994-1995
        - Nov. 23-28, “Africa's Future and the World,” Maastricht, Netherlands (Box I:54)
          - Background material, 1991-1995, (2 folders)
          - General, 1995-1996
      - 1996
        - Feb. 3-4, cochairmens' meeting, Gaborone, Botswana
        - Apr. 20-21, cochairpersons' meeting, Washington, D.C.
      - 1997, Oct. 31-Nov. 2, Political Committee and Policy Forum, Maputo, Mozambique, 1997-1998
      - 1998, Oct.. 19-21, “African Development Towards the 21st Century,” Second Tokyo International Conference on African Development, Tokyo, Japan
        - Background material, 1997
        - General, 1998
      - 1999, Apr. 9-10, “Promoting Agricultural Productivity and Competitiveness in Sub-Saharan Africa,” Nairobi, Kenya, 1997-1999 (Box I:55)
    - General, 1990-1999, (6 folders)
    - Printed matter, 1992-1996 (Box I:56)
    - Proposals and resolutions to create a global coalition for Africa, 1990
    - Reports, 1993
  - Goldman, Sachs & Co., 1981-1990, (3 folders)
  - Gorbachev Foundation USA, 1993
  - Greater Washington Research Center, Task Force on Local Government
    - 1981-1982, Oct.
    - 1982, Nov.-Dec. (Box I:57)
  - Harry S. Truman Research Institute for the Advancement of Peace, 1990
  - Independent Commission on Population and Quality of Life, 1992-1993
  - Indira Gandhi Memorial Trust, conferences and meetings
    - 1991, Nov. 17-20, “Challenges of the 21st Century,” third conference, New Delhi, India, 1990-1991
    - 1992, Nov. 18-20, Indira Gandhi Prize, International Jury, New Delhi, India, 1991-1992
    - 1993, Nov. 18-24, “Redefining the Good Society,” fourth conference, New Delhi, India
    - 1994, Nov., Indira Gandhi Prize, International Jury, New Delhi, India
    - 1997, Nov. 19-22, “Post Colonial World Inter-dependence and Identities,” sixth conference, New Delhi, India
    - 1999, Nov. 19-22, “New Century: Whose Century?” seventh conference, New Delhi, India
      - Background material, 1999
      - General, 1999
      - Indira Gandhi Prize, International Jury, 1999 (Box I:58)
  - Initiative for Peace and Cooperation in the Middle East
    - Blue Ribbon Commission meetings
      - 1993, Apr. 30-May 2, Ashford Castle, Ireland
        - Background book, 1993
        - General, 1992-1993
      - 1994, Jan. 10-13, Cairo, Egypt
        - Background book, 1994
        - General, 1993-1994
    - Council on Foreign Relations discussion on West Bank and Gaza, Washington, D.C., 1993
    - General, 1991-1993
  - Institute for East-West Security Studies, 1988-1989
  - Institute of Politics, John F. Kennedy School of Government, Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass.
    - General, 1978-1988
    - Meetings, 1977-1986, (4 folders) (Box I:59)
  - Institute on Global Conflict and Cooperation
    - Correspondence, 1990-1996
    - Meeting, International Advisory Board (Jan. 1995), La Jolla, Calif., 1994-1995
  - InterAction Council, meetings
    - 1992, May 28-31, Queretaro, Mexico
    - 1993
      - Jan. 21-23, “Bringing Africa Back into the Mainstream of the International System,” Cape Town, South Africa
        - Background material, 1991-1993
        - General, 1992-1993 (Box I:60)
      - May 13-16, Shanghai, China
        - Background material, 1992-1993
        - General, 1992-1993
    - 1994, June 7-9, Dresden, Germany
    - 1995, May 23-25, Tokyo, Japan, 1994-1995
    - 1998, May 3-5, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, 1997-1998
  - Inter-American Dialogue
    - Correspondence, 1985-1992
    - Reports, 1985-1989
  - International Center for Public Enterprises, 1991-1992 (Box I:61)
  - International Federation of Institutes for Advanced Study, 1984-1988
  - International Food Policy Research Institute
    - Meetings, “A 2020 Vision for Food, Agriculture, and the Environment”
      - 1995, Feb. 8, Stockholm, Sweden, 1994-1995
      - 1999, Apr. 14-15, Accra, Ghana, 1998-1999
    - Miscellany, 1997
  - International Foundation for the Survival and Development of Humanity
    - Correspondence, 1988-1993
    - General, 1988-1991, (2 folders)
  - International Fund for Agricultural Research, 1992
  - International Irrigation Management Institute (Box I:62)
    - Correspondence, 1988-1995, (2 folders)
    - Meetings
      - 1990
        - Jan. 31-Feb. 5, Colombo, Sri Lanka, 1989-1990
        - Nov. 26-29, Tokyo, Japan, 1988-1990
      - 1992, Jan. 21-Feb. 1, Hague, Netherlands
      - 1993, Dec. 2-5, Colombo, Sri Lanka
      - 1994
        - Apr. 7-9, Colombo, Sri Lanka
        - Nov. 27-Dec. 2, Colombo, Sri Lanka
    - Studies and reports
      - Miscellaneous, 1990-1993
      - Strategic planning, 1988-1993
      - Yudelman, Monty, consultant study on food production and sustainable irrigated agriculture, 1992-1993 (Box I:63)
  - International Research Center-Istanbul, 1989
  - Jennings Randolph Program for International Peace, 1995-1996
  - Kettering Foundation, China-U.S. Dialogue meetings
    - 1997, Sept. 22-25, Beijing, China
    - 1998, Oct. 5-7, Washington, D.C.
      - Background material, 1986, 1997-1998
      - Briefing book, 1998
      - General, 1998
    - 2000, Oct. 31-Nov. 2, Beijing, China
      - Background material
      - Briefing book (Box I:64)
      - General
  - Lawyers Alliance for World Security
    - Board meeting, 1999
    - General, 1995-2000, (2 folders)
    - International delegation visits to NATO countries
      - 1999, Sept. 23-29, Prague, Czech Republic; Rome, Italy; Berlin, Germany
        - Background material, 1997-1999
        - General, 1999
      - 2000, Mar., Paris, France, and London, England
  - Liu Center for the Study of Global Issues, International Advisory Council meeting, Vancouver, Canada, 1999
  - Middle Powers Initiative (Box I:65)
    - General, 1998-1999
    - Meetings, 1999
      - Mar. 11, U.S. delegation visit to Ottawa, Canada, 1998-2000
      - Nov. 4-6, delegation meeting, Tokyo, Japan
  - National Academy of Sciences, Issues in Science and Technology, 1984-1991, (2 folders)
  - National Commission on America without Roe, 1991-1992
  - National Commission on the Public Service, 1987-1991
  - National Committee on United States-China Relations (Box I:66)
    - Briefing book, 1994
    - Conferences and meetings
      - Twenty-fifth anniversary of the Shanghai Communiqué, 1997
      - “United States-China Dialogue”
        - 1984, Sept. 6-9, symposium, Tarrytown, N.Y., 1983-1984
        - 1985, Oct. 10-25, Tianjin, China
          - Background material, 1984-1985, (2 folders)
        - 1985 (Box I:67)
          - General, 1985
          - Notebooks and notes, 1985
        - 1987, Apr. 2-5, third dialogue, Racine, Wis., 1986-1987
        - 1989, June 21-23, discussions, Beijing, China, 1988-1989
        - 1990, Feb.-26-Mar. 1, fourth dialogue, Beijing, China
          - Briefing book, 1990
          - General, 1989-1990
          - Transcripts, 1990 (Box I:68)
        - 1991, June 14-17, fifth dialogue, Racine, Wis.
          - Background material, 1989-1991
          - General, 1991
        - 1993, Mar. 31-Apr. 10, sixth dialogue, Beijing, China
          - Background material, 1992-1993
          - General, 1993
        - 1994, Oct. 7-10, seventh dialogue, Pocantico Hills, N.Y.
      - Miscellany, 1994-2002
      - Press clippings, 1987-1990 (Box I:69)
      - Reports, 1988-1989, 1996
  - National Institute for the Environment, 1994-1995
  - Nature Conservancy, 1991
  - Orville and Jane Freeman Center for International Economic Policy, 1989-1992
  - Overseas Development Council
    - Correspondence, 1996
    - Conferences and meetings
      - 1982, Jan. 20, press luncheon, Washington, D.C., 1981-1982
      - 1991
      - 1998
        - Mar. 19, “Asia's Coming Population Explosion,” Washington, D.C.
        - Mar. 20, Board of Directors, Washington, D.C., (2 folders)
        - Oct. 13-14, Board of Directors, London, England (Box I:70)
          - Briefing book, 1998
          - General, 1998
      - 1999, Mar. 19, Board of Directors, Washington, D.C.
    - Reunión International Sobre el Cooperación y Desarrollo (Cancún Summit), background reports, 1981
    - Twenty-fifth anniversary, 1995
  - Parliamentarians Global Action, 1989-1990
  - Philadelphia Liberty Medal, International Selection Commission, 1994-1995
  - Policy Advisory Council, 1991
  - Population Action International
    - Correspondence, 1968, 1979-1994
    - “The Population Problem: Time Bomb or Myth?” page proofs, 1984 (Box I:71)
  - President's Special Review Board, 1986-1987
  - Project Independence Advisory Committee, 1974
  - Pugwash Conferences on Science and World Affairs
    - Correspondence, 1982-1993
    - Workshops
      - 1994, Dec. 10-11, twenty-third workshop on nuclear forces, Geneva, Switzerland
      - 1998
        - Feb. 21-22, twenty-seventh workshop on nuclear forces, Geneva, Switzerland, 1997-1998
        - July 14-18, fifth workshop on “The Future of the Nuclear Weapon Complexes of Russia and the USA,” Sarov and Moscow, Russia
          - Background material, 1997-1998
          - General, 1998
      - 2001, Mar. 25-27, “Moving Towards the Abolition of Nuclear Weapons,” New Delhi, India (Box I:72)
        - Background material, 1996-2001
        - General, 2000-2001
  - Rajiv Gandhi Foundation, memorial lecture
    - Correspondence, 1991-1992
    - Speech drafts, “A Global Population Policy to Advance Human Development in the 21st Century,” 1992
  - Refugee Studies Programme, 1992-1993
  - Rockefeller Foundation
    - General, 1983-1986, 1993-1999
    - Graham, Thomas, 1993-1996
    - Task Force on Development, 1985-1987
    - Trip, New Delhi, India, 1993-1994
  - Rockefeller University Council, New York, N.Y., 1982-1987
  - Rocky Mountain Institute, 1988-1989 (Box I:73)
  - Russian-American Press and Information Center, 1993
  - Save the Children, 1991-1992
  - Shriver Center, College Park, Md., 1993-1995
  - South Africa Free Elections Fund, 1993
  - Stanford University, Stanford, Calif.
    - Correspondence, 1987-1989
    - Graduate School of Business Advisory Council, 1987-1995
  - Tate Energy and Resources Institute, 1991-1996
  - Technoserve, 1987-1993
  - Trilateral Commission, meetings
    - 1987, Mar. 20-23, San Francisco, Calif., 1986-1987
    - 1992, Apr. 25-27, Lisbon, Portugal
    - 1999, Mar. 13-15, annual meeting, Washington, D.C., 1998-1999 (Box I:74)
  - U.S. Committee for START II, 1995, 1998-1999
  - United Nations Association of the United States of America, International Panel meetings
    - 1986
      - May 9-10, Washington, D.C., 1985-1986
      - Oct. 31-Nov. 1, Washington, D.C.
        - Background material and drafts, 1986
        - General, 1986
    - 1988, Apr. 29, New York N.Y.
  - United States-Japan Foundation
    - General, 1992-1994
    - Meetings
      - 1987, May 25-26, Tokyo, Japan
      - 1992, May 18-19, Kamamoto, Japan, 1991-1992 (Box I:75)
      - 1993, Apr. 18-20, Osaka, Japan
      - 1994
        - Apr. 17-19, Hiroshima, Japan, and Lanai, Hawaii
        - Oct. 24-26, Global Environmental Action, Tokyo, Japan
  - University of California, Berkeley, Calif., 1984-1993
  - Urban Institute, “Think Tanks and Public Policy,” Tokyo, Japan, 1995
    - Background material, 1993-1995
    - Drafts and policy papers, 1994-1995
    - General, 1994-1995
  - Washington Council on Non-Proliferation, 1990-1993
  - Willy Brandt International Foundation, 1990
  - World Commission on Water for the 21st Century, meetings, 1999 (Box I:76)
    - Mar. 22-23, Cairo, Egypt
      - Background material and drafts, 1997-1999
      - General, 1998-1999
      - Report, 1998
    - Aug. 9-10, Stockholm, Sweden
      - Background material and drafts, 1999
      - General, 1999
  - World Federation of United Nations Associations
    - General
      - 1988-1989, Jan.
      - 1989, Mar.-1990 (Box I:77)
    - Strong, Maurice, Global Security and Risk Management Steering Group, 1989
  - World Future Society, 1983-1996
  - Yosemite Institute, 1981-1983
- Part I: Subject File, 1960-2003 (Box I:77-104)
  Correspondence, memoranda, conferences and meetings, policy and research papers, reports and studies, drafts and typescripts, background material, briefing books, notes, transcripts, statements and testimony, speeches and writings, financial and legal records, press releases, printed matter, and miscellaneous material.
  - Aging, 1988 (Box I:77)
  - Agriculture
    - Committee on Agricultural Sustainability for Developing Countries, 1994-1995
    - Food and nutrition, 1983-1985
  - Archives and personal papers
    - Correspondence, 1968, 1977-1980
    - John F. Kennedy Library, Boston, Mass.
      - Bay of Pigs invasion, Paramilitary Study Group report, part III, 1960-1961, 1977, 1985
        - Annex nos. 1-24, (2 folders)
        - Annex nos. 25-30 (Box I:78)
      - Correspondence, 1968, 1974-2001
    - Library of Congress, 1978, 1984-1990, 1996
    - National Archives and Records Administration, 1969-1971, 1990-1992
  - Arms control and nuclear weapons
    - Anti-Ballistic Missile Treaty, 1985-1987
    - “Beyond Deterrence: The Future of Nuclear Weapons,” transcript, Center for Science and International Affairs, John F. Kennedy School of Government, Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass., 1983-1986
    - Committee on Nuclear Policy, 1997
    - Correspondence, 1968-1970, 1985-1988
    - Intermediate-Range Nuclear Forces Treaty, 1987-1988
    - Memoranda for the president, 1965-1966
    - Press conference, 1987 (Box I:79)
    - Statements in support of the abolition of nuclear weapons
      - International heads of state and civilian leaders, 1998
      - Joint statement of religious and military leaders, 1998-1999
    - Strategic Arms Limitation Talks (SALT II), 1972, 1987 See also Classified
    - Strategic Defense Initiative (“Star Wars”)
      - General, 1982-1985, (2 folders)
      - Notes, 1984-1986
      - Nuclear strategy, printed matter and statements
        - Indexed
          - 1982-1985, June, (2 folders)
          - 1985, July-1987, (3 folders) (Box I:80)
        - Miscellaneous, 1968-1969, 1980-1987
      - Office of Technology Assessment Advisory Panel, 1984-1985 See also Classified, (2 folders)
      - Printed matter (Box I:81)
        - Indexed
          - Set I, 1984-1986, (4 folders)
          - Set II, 1984-1985
        - Miscellaneous, 1984-1987
      - Speeches by others, 1984-1985
      - Testimony, Senate Committee on Appropriations, Subcommittee on Defense, 1986 (Box I:82)
  - Campaign for Oxford, University of Oxford, Oxford, England, 1988
  - Chemical weapons, 1984-1985
  - Clifford, Clark, Bank of Credit and Commerce International scandal, 1991
  - Commissions
    - Commission on CIA Activities within the Unites States (Rockefeller Commission) See Container I:87, Select Committee to Study Governmental Operations with Respect to Intelligence Activities (Church Committee)
    - President's Commission on White House Fellowships, 1990-1993
    - Rivlin Commission, 1994
  - Conferences and meetings
    - 1984
      - Oct. 15, Carnegie Corp., New York, N.Y.
      - Oct. 19, “The United States as a Debtor Country,” Institute for International Economics, Washington D.C.
    - 1986
      - July 7-11, Conference on Avoiding Nuclear War, Jackson Hole, Wyo.
      - Dec. 5, Committee for the Moral Evaluation of Nuclear Deterrence, National Conference of Catholic Bishops, Washington, D.C., 1983-1986
    - 1987
      - Jan. 8-9, “The Presidency and the Constitution,” Carter Presidential Center, Atlanta, Ga., 1986-1987
      - Jan. 23-24, Bilateral Commission on the Future of U.S.-Mexican Relations, Mexico City, Mexico, and Apr. 23-25, Washington, D.C., 1986-1987
      - Apr. 21, Institute for a Democratic Alternative for South Africa, Metropolitan Club, Washington, D.C., 1986-1987
      - July 1-3, Bellagio Conference on Tropical Forestry, Bellagio, Italy, 1986-1987
    - 1990
      - June 14-22, discussions with World Bank staff concerning environmental problems in Nigeria, Africa
        - Background material and drafts, 1988-1990
        - General, 1990 (Box I:83)
      - July 2-4, Africa Conference, Maastricht, Netherlands
        - General, 1990
        - Reports, 1990
        - Speeches and statements, 1990
      - July 19, “START II,” Security Options discussion group, Washington, D.C.
    - 1991
      - May 13-15, “Africa's Development Crisis,” Tokyo Forum, United Nations Capital Development Fund, Tokyo, Japan
      - Sept. 7-9, Third African Population Advisory Committee meeting, Paris, France, 1990-1991
    - 1992 (Box I:84)
      - Apr. 13-14, International Conference on the New International Order, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, 1990-1992
      - May 14-16, Commemoration Ceremony of the Twentieth Anniversary of the Reversion of Okinawa, symposium, Tokyo, Japan See also Classified
      - Sept. 17-18, Soviet Commission, John F. Kennedy School of Government, Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass.
    - 1993
      - Jan. 7, “Program on Cooperative Security,” Carnegie Corp. of New York, Washington D.C.
      - Mar. 17-18, “How to Promote Philanthropy: The Role of Japan in Contributing to Society,” Tokyo, Japan
        - Background material, 1991-1993
        - General, 1993
      - Nov. 15-16, publication of Cuba on the Brink by James G. Blight, Bruce J. Allyn, and David A. Welch, Miami, Fla., 1993-1994
    - 1994
      - July 22-24, “Change: Social Conflict or Harmony?” United Nations Development Programme, Stockholm, Sweden
      - Sept. 28-Oct. 1, “Non-Proliferation and Arms Control after the Cold War,” U.S.-Japan Study Group Conference, Tokyo, Japan
      - Oct. 12-13, World Food Prize, Des Moines, Iowa (Box I:85)
      - Nov. 1-3, Sino-U.S. Conference, Washington, D.C.
      - Nov. 10-11, Earth Council, San José, Costa Rica
      - Nov. 17-18, “Asia's Future and the World,” Create 21, Asahi Forum, Tokyo, Japan
        - Background material and drafts, 1994
        - General, 1994
    - 1995
      - Jan. 15-19, Centre for Policy Research, Goa, India, 1992-1995
      - Feb. 9-10, Consultative Group on International Agricultural Research, Lucerne, Switzerland, 1994
      - Oct. 16-18, “Moving Africa into the 21st Century,” North South Roundtable on Africa, Johannesburg, South Africa
    - 1997
      - Feb. 2-4, Microcredit Summit, Washington, D.C., 1995-1997, (3 folders)
      - Feb. 20-25, Shanghai Initiative, Round III, Islamabad, Pakistan, 1995-1997
      - Apr. 9-11, “Nuclear Energy–Let's Talk Now,” Japan Atomic Industrial Forum, Tokyo, Japan (Box I:86)
    - 1998
      - Mar. 23-24, African Population Advisory Committee, The Hague, Netherlands
        - Background material, 1989-1998, (2 folders)
        - General, 1998
      - Sept. 14-16, political simulation of Buenos Aires climate change negotiations, U.S. Army War College, Carlisle, Pa.
    - 1999
      - Oct. 10-15, “Global Integrity,” Ninth International Anti-Corruption Conference, Durban, South Africa
      - Oct. 24-25, Shanghai Initiative, Fourth Round, Warrenton, Va., 1994-2000
      - Nov. 7-10, First International Conference on AIDS in Ethiopia, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia
    - 2001, Feb. 8, Multilateral Development Banks Advisory Commission, Washington, D.C.
  - Congressional hearings (Box I:87)
    - House of Representatives
      - Committee on Foreign Affairs, 1985-1987
      - Committee on the Budget, 1990-1991
      - Statements and testimony, 1985
    - Senate
      - Committee on Foreign Relations
        - Correspondence, 1990-1991
        - Statements and testimony, 1984-1990
      - Select Committee to Study Governmental Operations with Respect to Intelligence Activities (Church Committee)
        - Correspondence, 1975
        - Press clippings, 1975
        - Statement and notes by McNamara, 1975
      - Statements and testimony, 1983-1989
  - Council for a Livable World Education Fund, 1989-1991
  - Cuban Missile Crisis, twenty-fifth anniversary (Box I:88)
    - Conferences, 1987
      - Mar. 5-8, Hawk's Cay Conference, Marathon, Fla.
      - Oct. 11-12, Cambridge Conference, Cambridge, Mass.
    - General, 1982-1988
    - Interviews, 1987
  - Defense department
    - Balance of payments, 1968
    - Letter of departure to Lyndon B. Johnson, 1968 (Box I:89)
    - Letters of farewell, 1968
    - Memoranda for the president, 1961-1969
    - Miscellany, 1968
    - Offers and proposals for post-defense service, 1967-1968
    - “Papers of Secretary of Defense McNamara,” index, 1968
    - Post-defense issues
      - Budgets, 1982-1987
      - Correspondence, 1970, 1976-1980, 1987
      - Defense Secretary's Commission on Base Realignment and Closure, hearing transcript, 1988
      - Legal cases
        - Agent Orange product liability litigation, 1983-1987
        - Bolanos v. Robert McNamara, 1995 (Box I:90)
        - LSD (drug) experimentation cases
          - Miscellaneous, 1978-1980
          - Thornwell v. United States, 1978-1981
        - Westmoreland v. CBS, Inc.
          - Background material
            - Extracts from public statements, 1967-1968
            - Tuchman, Barbara Wertheim, The March of Folly, 1984